

Sales Enquiry/Helpline 1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211

Email Print

- Send Email
- Preview
- Modify



Bipul Kumar premium Featured

Associate Director, Seeking Roles in New Business Development, Category Management, General Management, Fund Raising, Business Strategy, Vendor Development, Investor Relations, Business Expansion, Product Management, Market Research, Strategic Business Planning

- Current Designation: Associate Director Business Development
- Current Company: Flipkart.com
- Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore
- Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore
- Functional Area: Marketing / Advertising / MR / PR
- Role: Head/VP/GM-Mktg
- *Industry:* Internet/Ecommerce
- Date of Birth / Gender: 05 Jan 1985 / Male
- Marital Status: Married
- *Total Experience*: 11 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
- Annual Salary: Rs 80+ Lac(s)
- Notice Period: 1 Month
- Highest Degree: MBA/PGDM [Marketing]
- Address: Palm 611, SJR Park Vista, Sarjapur Road, Bangalore 560004
- Key Skills: Associate Director, Head / VP / GM Marketing, New Business Development, Category Management, Fund Raising, Business Strategy, Vendor Development, Investor Relations, Business Expansion, Product Management, Market Research, Strategic Business Planning

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

ID: 322f1dc502d9583f66Last Active: Oct-Dec 2019Last Modified: Oct-Dec 2019

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Summary

Bipul has more than 9 years of experience in e - commerce, technology and start-ups. Bipul has founded a company in the field of e - commerce apart from working with Flipkart.com (India) in his latest endeavour. Bipul has worked on conceptualizing and building disruptive business models in multiple categories in his ongoing stint in e-commerce industry. During his own start-up, he worked on building one of India's earliest e -commerce platforms. Bipul has led teams in international and national environments, integrating business processes and driving new initiatives.

Work Experience

Flipkart.com as Associate Director Business Development

Aug 2014 to Till Date

Flipkart is India's number one e - Commerce Company with presence in more than 100 categories and a valuation of USD 20 billion in 10 years of existence.

Business Head - Mobile Accessories Business (May'18 - Present)

Complete P&L responsibility for USD 250 million mobile accessories business

Business, Process, capability and customer experience ownership

Responsible for structurally scaling the category bringing in innovative tech intervention

Category Head - IOT, Tablet and IT Peripheral (June'16 - April'18)

Complete P&L responsibility for USD 100 million business across these three categories

Business, Process, capability and customer experience ownership

Won multiple Industry awards and recognition for launching and scaling different businesses

Category Head - Automobile and branded auto accessories (April'15 - May'16)

Lead the launch of sale of 4 wheeler/2 wheeler/alternate transport category on Flipkart

End to end business planning and execution of the category

Financial modelling, process and product development for the launch

Strategic partnerships with various national and International brands for the launch

International sourcing project to build unique international selection

Category Launch - Food, Pet Supplies, Eye Care and Home Care (Jan'15 - March'15)

Led seller acquis ion portfolio for launch of these categories on Flipkart

Developed seller acquis ion framework, comprehensive market research to identify and on board strategic sellers on Flipkart

Strategic partnership with various national and international brands for the launch

Worked on identifying sellers for hyperlocal pilot which was eventually spun off as a separate venture

Represented Flipkart as speaker at various food conferences

Category Management - Books (Aug'14 - Dec'14)

Managed e - learning, Test Prep, International and regional books portfolio contributing to 45% of the overall books category

Relaunched regional books portfolio with 50000 selection in 8 Indian languages

Worked with strategic international suppliers for growth of International business. Represented Flipkart at various international book conferences/Fairs

Sportsnlife.com as *Founder/CEO*

Jan 2011 to Jun 2014

Sportsnlife was one of India's earliest e-commerce venture and disrupted sports, Fitness and Adventure categories with online retail As the founder CEO, built and grew sportsnlife from scratch:

Built the e- commerce platform with cutting edge technology leading the architecture, design and functionality

Built and led a rock star team across business, technology, operations and logistics

100+ brand partnership with 12 exclusive online distribution of international brands

Raised angel investment for growth

Successfully exited the venture after 3 years of building and scaling up.

Tatsam Sports Pvt. Ltd., as Founder

Jan 2008 to Jun 2014

Tatsam Sports was an end to end sports solutions company with an expertise in consulting, Infrastructure planning and Development, Equipment and Events

As a Founder/CEO of Tatsam Sports

Carved the vision for Tatsam Sports:

Built the foundation for solutions currently offered by Tatsam Sports

Built a team which independently runs the operations for Tatsam Sports

Acquired 100+ B2B customers

Formed an advisory board with the combined experience of more than 85 years

Led the foray of Tatsam into e - commerce with the inception of sportsnlife.com

Advised start-ups as a part of their advisory boards and helped them develop prototypes, go to market, scale - up and fund raise Spearheaded the entire operation of Tatsam including new initiatives, business strategy and planning, fund raising, team building and external communications

Tatsam received numerous awards and recognitions including Businessworld Young Entrepreneur Award 2011, Indira Innovation Award 2011, NEN First Dot Award and featured in media like Mint, Outlook Money, Russia Times, Business world among others

Guest lecturer in many premier B- schools and speaker at various entrepreneurship forums/events

^ Back to Top

Education

- UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Mechanical) from Visveswaraiah Technological University (VTU) in 2007
- PG: MBA/PGDM (Marketing) from Institute of Management Technology (IMT), Ghaziabad in 2011

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name VersionLast UsedExperience

MS OFFICE 2015 7 Year(s) MAGENTO 2015 7 Year(s)

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language Proficiency Read Write Speak

Hindi Expert
English Expert

*\times Back to Top

Affirmative Action

• Category: General

• Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

• Job Type: Permanent

• Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Important

• Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld.

<u>Careers</u> - <u>About Us</u> - <u>Clients</u> - <u>Terms & Conditions</u> - <u>FAQ's</u> - <u>Contact Us</u> - <u>Report a Problem</u> - <u>Site Map</u> - <u>Resources</u> Our Partners: <u>Jeevansathi Matrimonials</u> - <u>ICICIcommunities.org</u> - <u>99acres</u> - <u>Real Estate In India</u> All rights reserved © 2019 Info Edge India Ltd.